<ArrayOfCaseStudyDump xmlns="http://schemas.datacontract.org/2004/07/REFAPIService" xmlns:i="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
<CaseStudyDump>
<CaseStudyId>999</CaseStudyId>
<Continent><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>6255148</GeoNamesId><Name>Europe</Name></GeoLocation><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>6255149</GeoNamesId><Name>North America</Name></GeoLocation><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>6255147</GeoNamesId><Name>Asia</Name></GeoLocation></Continent><Country><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>1269750</GeoNamesId><Name>India</Name></GeoLocation><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>3077311</GeoNamesId><Name>Czech Republic</Name></GeoLocation><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>6252001</GeoNamesId><Name>United States</Name></GeoLocation></Country><Funders xmlns:a="http://schemas.microsoft.com/2003/10/Serialization/Arrays"><a:string>Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council</a:string><a:string>Council for the Central Laboratory of the Research Councils</a:string><a:string>Royal Society</a:string></Funders><ImpactDetails>&#xD;    AVX Ulster has had on-going links with AVX Ltd for over 25 years&#xD;      with the company funding research, providing PhD studentships and offering&#xD;      industrial support for numerous collaborative R&amp;amp;D projects. Most&#xD;      recently (2009), NIBEC and AVX commenced a large scale project to improve&#xD;      the quality of the dielectric layers in the Multi-Layer Ceramic Capacitors&#xD;      (MLCC) that the company produce in millions of units per day. This project&#xD;      was highly successful with major improvements in nanoparticle dispersion&#xD;      which the company have now fully integrated by into their volume&#xD;      production lines (including Czech Republic). This has had a major impact&#xD;      upon product development and business results [4]. [text removed for&#xD;      publication]. Building on the success of this collaboration, in 2012 AVX&#xD;      co-funded a second project in collaboration with NIBEC specifically&#xD;      focusing on improvement of the base metal electrode (BME) system utilising&#xD;      nanoparticle nickel for MLCCs. This project has already identified&#xD;      improvements in BME ink formulation and processing. [text removed for&#xD;      publication]. This has arisen due to the direction and outputs achieved&#xD;      from the materials characterisation and the understanding associated with&#xD;      electrical characterisation of both raw materials and devices. Improved&#xD;      control of de-agglomeration and dispersion of barium titanate powders and&#xD;      metal oxide dopants along with feedback from nanoscale measurement and&#xD;      characterisation data (impedance analysis, dispersion and binder-particle&#xD;      interaction) have allowed the company to greatly enhance their&#xD;      manufacturing processes [1, 4]. A third and much larger project (&amp;#163;4m) has&#xD;      recently been submitted to Invest NI (July 2013) focusing on defect&#xD;      control within the dielectrics layers. Furthermore, the knowledge gained&#xD;      through our recent collaborative activities has allowed AVX (NI) to gain&#xD;      substantial credibility with USA customers such as NASA, BMW, Ford and the&#xD;      European Space Agency. New device characterisation and fabrication&#xD;      capabilities introduced by NIBEC include, Electrical Impedance&#xD;      Spectroscopy, FIB preparation of lamellae and HRTEM analysis, XPS and&#xD;      ToF-SIMs, particle size analysis (BET, electroacoustic and dynamic light&#xD;      scattering), new wetting and dispersion technology and a rare earth dopant&#xD;      programme. All of these interactions have impacted on international sales,&#xD;      growth, global market penetration and job sustainability. Joint&#xD;      publications, publicity and sponsored PhD programmes have resulted,&#xD;      leading to a strong and fruitful relationship.&#xD;    SiSaf Ltd.: SiSaf is a spin-in to NIBEC and is developing drug&#xD;      delivery formulations that use a patented bioactive and non-toxic form of&#xD;      silicon nanoparticles (&amp;#8804; 50nm) that are designed to allow compounds to&#xD;      penetrate into the deeper layers of the skin without adverse effects [2].&#xD;      Using the extensive knowledgebase acquired over the last 15 years in the&#xD;      area of nanomaterials, NIBEC is assisting the company to develop improved&#xD;      fabrication and characterisation techniques. NIBEC have a senior staff&#xD;      representative on the board as CSO (JMcL). SiSafs core fabrication and&#xD;      characterisation laboratories are based at NIBEC and with the investment&#xD;      of two joint &amp;#163;250k INI R&amp;amp;D grants, various consultancies and&#xD;      collaborative work, NIBEC and SiSaf have jointly developed a wide range of&#xD;      capabilities in silicon nanoparticle production. This work has led to an&#xD;      expansion of SiSaf to seven staff, increased laboratory space and&#xD;      enhancement of their patent, IP and knowledge assets. High quality silicon&#xD;      nanoparticles (50-100nm) are routinely batch-produced, functionalised,&#xD;      doped with drugs and characterised for trials and marketing samples to&#xD;      customers.&#xD;    This interaction has already led to a better understanding of the&#xD;      fundamental properties of Si nanoparticles, its dependence of the&#xD;      formulation route and a more efficient processing protocol. The research&#xD;      has directly impacted on the valuation of the company with NIBEC staff&#xD;      producing key reports and know-how in a number of important areas, namely:&#xD;      the nature, size and surface characteristics of the 50 nm silicon&#xD;      nanoparticles; three technical reports on the scale-up viability for&#xD;      nanoparticle production via (i) arc deposition, (ii) via - milling and&#xD;      (iii) via Pulsed Laser Deposition (PLD) for production of smaller&#xD;      particles. Biocompatibility (and in particular nano-toxicity) has been&#xD;      investigated by NIBEC and a technical report issued which has impacted&#xD;      beneficially on investor confidence through our findings of non-toxicity&#xD;      which would have been a major barrier to full commercialisation. The&#xD;      company now has a valuation of &amp;#163;3.5m and is completing a set of &amp;#163;1.5m&#xD;      human trials in the USA to determine the suitability of the product for&#xD;      topical application. It has a Silicon Valley office at ITLG with John&#xD;      Hartnett as lead investor along with IUL, Crescent Capital and a set of&#xD;      private angels [7,8]. The impact of having NIBEC team on board is&#xD;      significant and the following points were key to improving the company's&#xD;      overall value: nanoparticle fabrication (via plasma, CVD, wet etching and&#xD;      milling); nanoparticle characterisation via HRTEM, dynamic light&#xD;      scattering and zeta potential dispersion analysis, pharmaokinetics and&#xD;      nanotoxicity testing with human cell lines [2]. In summary the company is&#xD;      in a strong position, with over &amp;#163;2m of investment to date and with Human&#xD;      Clinical trials near completion, Suzanne Siebert (CEO) has said&#xD;        "NIBEC's impact on the company has been critical, and as we develop even&#xD;        stronger international relationships in India, USA and throughout&#xD;        Europe, these engineers, who underpin our work are highly important&#xD;        partners".&#xD;    SEAGATE: In 1994 the then core nanotechnology team at NIBEC, in&#xD;      conjunction with colleagues in QUB and local government agencies, were&#xD;      instrumental in attracting Seagate Technologies to locate a major&#xD;      production facility in the UK (in competition with South America, eastern&#xD;      Europe and Asia). The subsequent NIBEC relationships with Seagate R&amp;amp;D&#xD;      in both the UK and the USA were developed around nanoscale coatings of&#xD;      diamond-like carbon on a new generation of GMR read-write head devices.&#xD;      The NIBEC team utilised a novel plasma immersion technique called Filtered&#xD;      Cathodic Vacuum Arc (FCVA) that was developed in conjunction with Veeco&#xD;      Instruments (USA). This, along with our development of specific metrology&#xD;      protocols for analysing AlTiC ceramics, led to ultra-hard layers (30 GPa)&#xD;      with a credible measured thickness of 1.5nm, the world's thinnest&#xD;      continuous carbon coatings [3]. [text removed for publication]. The&#xD;      ultimate result was a read-write head with a significantly increased iron&#xD;      content and a reduction in head-disc flying-height (due to the protective&#xD;      nature of the dense carbon layer). [text removed for publication].&#xD;      Seagate, in conjunction with InvestNI, invested over &amp;#163;5m in three key&#xD;      projects associated with the augmentation of this initial work, from 1996&#xD;      to 2009. NIBEC and Seagate are currently planning a new programme of&#xD;      engagement in the area of Heat Assisted Magnetic Recording with a focus on&#xD;      our proven nanomaterials capability [3].&#xD;    </ImpactDetails><ImpactSummary>&#xD;    Nanomaterials research at Ulster into materials including diamond-like&#xD;      carbon (DLC) ultra-thin films, carbon nanotubes (CNT), graphene, silicon&#xD;      and metal oxide nanoparticles has resulted in direct uptake by major&#xD;      industrial manufacturers and led to a directly quantifiable socio-economic&#xD;      impact via added value, improved efficiencies and cost-savings and has&#xD;      secured or increased the employment of skilled engineering staff. Examples&#xD;      of this impact since 2008 include ceramic nanoparticles research in&#xD;      partnership with AVX Ltd that resulted in improved production efficiency&#xD;      processes (up 20%) and higher quality devices (up 10%). [text removed for&#xD;      publication] Research into ultra-thin DLC films, funded by Seagate, has&#xD;      led to their incorporation into magnetic media. [text removed for&#xD;      publication] Our nanoparticle research has attracted a new spin-in company&#xD;      SiSaf Ltd. (2009) and by incorporating NIBEC's expertise in nanomaterials&#xD;      into its business plan, the company was able to grow to a valuation of&#xD;      &amp;#163;3.5m and employ 7 people in skilled technical positions.&#xD;    </ImpactSummary><ImpactType>Technological</ImpactType><Institution>&#xD;    </Institution><Institutions><HEI><AlternativeName>Ulster (University of)</AlternativeName><InstitutionName>University of Ulster</InstitutionName><PeerGroup>66</PeerGroup><Region>Northern Ireland</Region><UKPRN>10007807</UKPRN></HEI></Institutions><Panel>B         </Panel><PlaceName/><References>&#xD;    
1. Okpalugo T, Papakonstantinou P, Murphy H, McLaughlin J, Brown N,&#xD;      (2005) "High resolution XPS characterization of chemical functionalised&#xD;      MWCNTs and SWCNTs" Carbon,Vol.43, pp 153-161&#xD;      DOI:10.1016/j.carbon.2004.08.033 (Cited 400 times)&#xD;    

2. Shang, N, Papakonstantinou, P, McMullan, M, Chu, M, Stamboulis,&#xD;      A,Potenza, A, Dhesi, S and Marchetto, H (2008) Catalyst-Free Efficient&#xD;      Growth, Orientation and Biosensing Properties of Multilayer Graphene&#xD;      Nanoflake Films with Sharp Edge Planes. Adv. Functional Mats, 18 (21). pp.&#xD;      3506-3514. DOI:10.1002/adfm.200800951 cited 250 times&#xD;    

3. Shang, NG, Papakonstantinou, P, Wang, P, Zakharov, A, Palnitkar, U,&#xD;      Lin, IN, Chu, M and Stamboulis, A Self-Assembled Growth,&#xD;      Microstructure, and FE High-Performance of Ultrathin Diamond-Nanorods.&#xD;      (2009) ACS NANO, 3 (4). pp. 1032-1038 DOI:10.1021/nn900167p&#xD;      (Nanofabrication and characterisation)&#xD;    

4. Papakonstantinou P, Zhao J F, Lemoine P, McAdams ET, McLaughlin JAD,&#xD;      (2002) "The effects of Si incorporation on the electrochemical and&#xD;      nanomechanical properties of DLC thin films", Diamond and Related&#xD;      Materials, Vol. 11, No. 3-6, Elsevier, Pages 1074-1080&#xD;      DOI:10.1016/S0925-9635(01)00656-2 (cited 90 times)&#xD;    
5. EPSRC: D Mariotti P Maguire et. al. EP/K022237/1 &amp;#163;692k (2012-2014)&#xD;      -nanoparticles&#xD;    6. EPSRC: J McLaughlin, P Maguire GR/L86319/01/Seagate &amp;#163;47k (1998-2001)&#xD;    </References><ResearchSubjectAreas><SubjectArea><Level1>9</Level1><Level2>12</Level2><Subject>Materials Engineering</Subject></SubjectArea><SubjectArea><Level1>3</Level1><Level2>1</Level2><Subject>Analytical Chemistry</Subject></SubjectArea><SubjectArea><Level1>3</Level1><Level2>3</Level2><Subject>Macromolecular and Materials Chemistry</Subject></SubjectArea></ResearchSubjectAreas><Sources>&#xD;    &#xD;      AVX: Statement of Evidence from Head of AVX (Coleraine) N1&#xD;      SiSaf: Statement of Evidence from CEO of SiSaf (www.sisaf.co.uk)&#xD;        N2&#xD;      Veeco-Seagate: Contact - Veeco-Seagate Account Manager N3&#xD;      Invest Northern Ireland: Contact Technology Executive (AVX and SiSaf&#xD;        reviewer) N4&#xD;      MATRIX: Contact Chair of MATRIX (Impact of NIBEC on Seagate/AVX/SiSaf)&#xD;        N5&#xD;      AVX Media: http://www.eri.ulster.ac.uk/uploads/documents/avx_nanoparicles_news.pdf&#xD;        N6&#xD;      SiSaf Media: http://www.eri.ulster.ac.uk/uploads/documents/sisaf_news.pdf&#xD;        N7&#xD;      SiSaf Investment Media: http://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/business/news/university-&#xD;biotech-firm-boosted-by-major-investment-from-silicon-valley-28603395.html&#xD;        N8&#xD;      Graphene/CNTs Media: N9 http://www.eri.ulster.ac.uk/uploads/documents/irish_times_article_pagona_nano(1).pdf
&#xD;      Graphene International Scale-Up: N10 http://www.eri.ulster.ac.uk/uploads/documents/industrial_scale_graphene_pagona.docx
&#xD;    &#xD;    </Sources><Title>&#xD;    Ulster - Bringing nanomaterials research to industrial production.&#xD;    </Title><UKLocation/><UKRegion/><UOA>Electrical and Electronic Engineering, Metallurgy and Materials</UOA><UnderpinningResearch>&#xD;    The Nanotechnology R&amp;amp;D activities within NIBEC have a coordinated&#xD;      focus on developing a fundamental understanding of how materials&#xD;      processing impacts on the resultant characteristics and properties of&#xD;      ultra-thin films (&amp;lt;2nm), nanoparticles and surface properties at the&#xD;      nanoscale [1-4]. We have an established track record in the preparation,&#xD;      analysis and processing of materials including diamond-like carbon (DLC),&#xD;      carbon nanotubes (CNT), graphene, and various nanoparticle systems (Si,&#xD;      group IV alloys, ferroelectric ceramics, and metal oxides). This area has&#xD;      received substantial support from EPSRC, the Royal Society, the EU&#xD;      Framework Programmes (FP4 - FP7) and InvestNI in collaboration with and/or&#xD;      through direct funded from industry (Seagate, AVX, SiSaf, Intel,&#xD;      Glaxo-Smith-Kline, Schrader Electronics, Analog Devices, TFX Medical,&#xD;      Medtronic, Labcoat, Kelvatech, Randox). The strategic aim of this research&#xD;      is to advance the understanding of nanomaterials for device fabrication&#xD;      and to promote its integration into advanced industrial manufacture [5].&#xD;      The associated publications highlight our expertise in fabrication &amp;amp;&#xD;      advanced characterisation that led to direct industry impact (PP, PM, PL).&#xD;    A number of targeted equipment grants have led to the creation of one of&#xD;      the most advanced academic nanomaterials research facilities in Europe&#xD;      (&amp;#163;15m of capital investment in the last 10 years from SRIF, RCIF, DEL,&#xD;      EPSRC)[6]. Recent highlights include novel equipment for the creation of&#xD;      ultra-thin carbon/CNT/graphene films, a nanoparticle production laboratory&#xD;      and advanced characterisation based on our new HRTEM. Our fundamental&#xD;      strengths have centred on; (i) advancing metrology for measuring&#xD;      nano-scale hardness, film thickness, internal stress and adhesive strength&#xD;      on ultra-thin (1-50nm) carbon layers; (ii) nanoparticle fabrication (via&#xD;      laser, microplasma, milling and wet chemical synthesis) and&#xD;      characterisation of both the materials and the synthesis processes; (iii)&#xD;      nano-scale surface-engineering and functionalisation with associated&#xD;      high-resolution analysis (HRTEM, ToF-SIMS, XPS). The recently established&#xD;      &amp;#163;2m nanoparticle laboratory is key to the synthesis, characterisation and&#xD;      understanding the unique properties of dispersed nanoparticles and it has&#xD;      attracted industry (AVX, Bombardier, SiSaf and Randox) to support our&#xD;      research.&#xD;    For material synthesis, our primary strength is in plasma-based&#xD;      deposition, surface engineering and functionalization. We have at hand a&#xD;      large number of plasma systems operating from DC up to microwave&#xD;      frequencies and from vacuum to atmospheric pressure. We host advanced&#xD;      pilot-scale industrial systems supplied through collaboration with&#xD;      equipment manufacturers. These include a custom-built microwave plasma&#xD;      system (Seiki, Japan), which was the world's first system for the&#xD;      deposition of highly oriented nanotubes [1- 3] and a FCVA - filtered&#xD;      cathodic vacuum arc system (NTI Technologies, Singapore) for the&#xD;      deposition of hydrogen-free highly diamond-like carbons for Seagate. The&#xD;      research groups involved have also designed and constructed a suite of&#xD;      advanced multi-functional plasma systems in-house, including pilot&#xD;      (reel-reel) production systems with integrated specialist diagnostic tools&#xD;      for concurrent measurement of plasma and material properties during the&#xD;      growth of nanoparticles. This facility is being further developed towards&#xD;      providing low- pressure and atmospheric pressure capabilities for general&#xD;      large area/low cost processing and precision three-dimensional coatings&#xD;      for medical implants. We have four patents awarded and active&#xD;      commercialisation in progress. Recently a University of Ulster spin-out&#xD;      company Surf Spec Ltd was established (BM) to exploit aspects of plasma&#xD;      surface modification as they apply to biomaterials. In-house materials&#xD;      characterisation is complemented by access to international synchrotron&#xD;      (Daresbury, Diamond, CERN) and neutron diffraction (Rutherford Appleton)&#xD;      facilities via numerous CCLRC and EU awards.&#xD;    We have secured funding for 15 projects related to nanomaterials and of&#xD;      these, two major research awards, totalling &amp;#163;1.6m since 2008, involve&#xD;      collaboration with AVX Ltd (TB, PL). The research aims to link&#xD;      fundamental ceramic nanoparticle properties to industrial processing&#xD;      conditions. The resultant impact on the electrical and reliability&#xD;      characteristics of multi-layer capacitor devices has allowed the company&#xD;      to develop a new generation of high value products. Core elements of this&#xD;      work along with the processing expertise developed are now also being&#xD;      targeted at the development of ceramic/clay fillers for Bombardier.&#xD;    SiSaf Ltd are a 2009 spin-in company with NIBEC staff on the board&#xD;      as CSO/Director. A collaborative research venture with NIBEC aims to&#xD;      produce and functionalise nanoparticle silicon for use in drug and&#xD;      therapeutic transdermal delivery applications (TB, JMcL, BM). This work&#xD;      relies on the provision of high-quality and precisely controlled 50nm&#xD;      particles of Si with defined porosity/surface properties in order to allow&#xD;      specific functionalisation and drug attachment. This has involved in-vitro&#xD;      testing of Si particle nano-toxicity at the NIBEC Cell Culture Facility&#xD;      (BM). The data has provided the platform for a vitamin C dissolution study&#xD;      in an animal model which indicated that the SiSaf delivery system is 30%&#xD;      better than a standard drug delivery system. Current studies are examining&#xD;      the use of nano-silicon for transdermal therapeutic delivery involving a&#xD;      USA based human clinical trial. SiSaf won the 2010 Award for Most&#xD;      Promising Technology at the Irish Technology Leadership Group (ITLG)&#xD;      awards ceremony in Silicon Valley, USA.&#xD;    The majority of the carbon-based ultra-thin film and nanoparticles work&#xD;      commenced in 2000 arising from the burgeoning global interest in&#xD;      diamond-like carbon (DLC), carbon nanotubes (CNT) and graphene for&#xD;      electrical, optical and mechanical applications (PM, PP JMcL). Our&#xD;      research was guided in the main via company initiated collaborations with&#xD;      Seagate Technology, Daewoo Electronics and TFX Medical [4,&#xD;      6]. Each company had a particular requirement for ultra- thin, low&#xD;      friction, dense (pin-hole free) and durable films of 1 nm (Seagate) - 20&#xD;      nm (TFX) in thickness. The experience gained in delivering the challenging&#xD;      specifications set down by these globally leading companies provided the&#xD;      model for the NIBEC technology transfer process and it is currently&#xD;      focussed on the controlled growth and properties of CNT arrays for&#xD;      biomedical and biosensor applications. Original work in the application of&#xD;      CNTs has led to the development of inventive electrochemical platforms for&#xD;      bio-sensing applications, several of which are now patent protected. Also&#xD;      a spin-out company, Graphene International Ltd (2012) has recently&#xD;      been established by PP with patents and licenses in the area of graphene&#xD;      production scale-up.&#xD;    </UnderpinningResearch>
</CaseStudyDump>

<CaseStudyDump><CaseStudyId>38363</CaseStudyId><Continent><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>6255148</GeoNamesId><Name>Europe</Name></GeoLocation></Continent><Country><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>3077311</GeoNamesId><Name>Czech Republic</Name></GeoLocation></Country>

<Funders xmlns:a="http://schemas.microsoft.com/2003/10/Serialization/Arrays"/>
<ImpactDetails>
    Through the longstanding interaction with AVX Ltd the company was aware
      of our unique academic research involving FIB micromachining allied to
      microscopy of ferroelectrics to reveal intrinsic behaviour and identify
      consequences of defects to capacitor behaviour.
    In 2011, AVX Ltd encountered a reliability problem concerning specific
      MLCC product ranges. Through their Tier 2 customers Lear Corporation and
      Johnson Controls Inc. who on behalf of their Tier 1 customer Volkswagen
      Group (for VW and Audi) reported that the Volkswagen Group had revised the
      environmental specification for MLCC (case sizes 0603 and 0805) for
      automotive applications [Source 1].
    Under revised environmental stress conditions at the customer site and
      subsequently replicated in the AVX Ltd. factory, of increased humidity and
      temperature, the supplied parts where exhibiting unacceptable failure
      rates. "The automotive industry is one of the most demanding markets
        for MLCC with failure rates often pushed toward no more than 1:109
      parts" [Source 1]. This arises because both the owner and
      the public on the road perceives particular brand of vehicle to have
      broken down and to not associate the breakdown with failure of a supply
      chain component.
    AVX Ltd made available a selection of operational and failed parts for
      our investigation along with a technical brief on their electrical testing
      to date on the basis that they "... were aware of the research in
        ceramic capacitors and in particular the innovative focused ion beam
        methods applied to ferroelectrics and capacitors that had been developed
        at Queen's" [Source 1].
    With our previous research in more sensitive nanoscale capacitors allied
      to our expertise acquired via the KTP project "handling `green' and
        finished parts" we were familiar at handling their commercial
      product and that was seen as `beneficial" [Source 1].
    A MLCC is comprised of a stack of several hundred interleaved
      ferroelectric ceramic and nickel electrode layers. Electric contact to the
      device is then made via end terminations of two layers of nickel and tin.
      The tin layer provides the region for solder contact to be made. In the
      particular product that exhibited failure the electrode is connected to
      the MLCC via a stress relieving silver-polymer composite layer.
    We were able to adapt and formulate a modification to our usual FIB based
      micromachining protocols used in the creation of nanoscale capacitors to
      develop a workflow that would allow us to extract representative sample
      pieces for evaluation and inspection. This adapted workflow meant that we
      were able to perform successional slicing of the MLCC's in a series of
      testing locations.
    Electron microscopy imaging and associated chemical analysis was
      performed on slices extracted and in regions from where they had been
      removed. It became evident that the failure under humidity test was not
      arising from damage to or degradation of the more sensitive ferroelectric
      ceramic material, but instead it was originating at the interface of the
      electrode layers and the ferroelectric ceramic.
    A major challenge, over the last fifteen or so years, in all research and
      engineering of ferroelectric capacitors has been the move away from noble
      metal electrodes and contacts to base metals such as nickel. Nickel will
      unfavourably oxidise at the interface with the oxide-based titanate
      ferroelectric. In this case of these failed parts further detailed
      examination on FIB machined sections led to an unexpected cause of the
      actual device failure. The final overcoat of tin was introducing
      additional stress due to a high deposition rate that was exacerbating the
      delamination of the nickel from the ferroelectric. That delamination then
      provided a path for the metal in the polymer composite to escape under
      application of voltage and caused part failure.
    A report [Source 2] of the investigation and outcomes was prepared
      and a de-briefing meeting at AVX Ltd arranged and the findings presented.
      In addition to the technical staff of AVX Ltd at Coleraine also present
      were engineers from their subsidiary plant in the Czech Republic that
      undertakes the electro-plating of the metal electrode layers.
    In addressing the reach and significance of this impact we note that
      while AVX Ltd is based in Coleraine, Northern Ireland (NI), they are part
      of AVX Corporation who are in turn part of Kyocera Electronic Devices in
      the Kyocera Group.
    As of 2012 AVX Ltd. employed 317 people in NI and had a &amp;#163;108M turnover;
      no profit figures are available [Source 3]. The factory operates a
      subsidiary activity in the Czech Republic. Product development and
      principal manufacture in undertaken in Coleraine and then the parts are
      shipped to the Czech Republic for the plating and sample testing before
      supply to customers.
    On the basis of our technical report and de-briefing meeting, informed by
      data acquired using our FIB micromachining protocols AVX Ltd were able to
      undertake timely revisions to their manufacturing program. This eradicated
      the part failures to an accepted tolerance level and thus allowed them to
      deliver on the contract to their Tier 2 customers Lear Corporation and
      Johnson Controls Inc. who then in turn supply to their Tier 1 customers VW
      and Audi [Source 1].
    AVX Ltd. have confirmed that the value of the international contract was
      "valued at $0.6M". [Source 1].
    </ImpactDetails><ImpactSummary>
    The provision of professional analysis and advice has created an economic
      impact of $0.6M with AVX Ltd, a leading supplier of electronic components
      within the Kyocera Group. This information was pivotal to AVX Ltd
      retaining a major contract, for multi-layer ceramic capacitor (MLCC's)
      supply through to the automotive manufacturer Volkswagen Group. Our
      intervention addressed a reliability issue in the MLCCs and allowed them
      to improve processes and revise manufacture protocols. The impact drew on
      previous collaborative research with AVX Ltd and innovative methodologies
      for preparation of micro and nanoscale samples of materials in capacitors
      in academic research.
    </ImpactSummary><ImpactType>Technological</ImpactType><Institution>
    Queen's University Belfast
    </Institution><Institutions><HEI><AlternativeName>Queen's University Belfast</AlternativeName><InstitutionName>Queen's University Belfast</InstitutionName><PeerGroup>65</PeerGroup><Region>Northern Ireland</Region><UKPRN>10005343</UKPRN></HEI></Institutions><Panel>B         </Panel><PlaceName/><References>
    For each reference we provide data on the journal ranking within ISI
      classification area/s by ISI Journal Impact Factor (IF), the actual
      Journal Impact Factor and the number of cites the article received on the
      ISI Web of Knowledge to September 2013.
    References 1-3 illustrate both quality of the underpinning research and
      evidence to the impact, while references 4-6 provide the latter.
    
[1] "Investigation of dead layer thickness in SrRuO3/Ba0.5Sr0.5TiO3/Au
        thin film capacitors", L. J. Sinnamon et al., Applied Physics
      Letters, 78, 1724 (2001). http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.1356731
      (17th of 125 in Physics &amp;#8212; Applied, IF 3.8, 123 cites).
    

[2] "Exploring grain size as a cause for "dead-layer" effects in thin
        film capacitors", L.J. Sinnamon, et al, Applied Physics Letters, 81,
      703 (2002). http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.1494837
      (17th of 125 in Physics &amp;#8212; Applied, IF 3.8, 77 cites).
    

[3] "Intrinsic dielectric response of ferroelectric nanocapacitors",
      M. M. Saad, et al, Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter 16, L451
      (2004). http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/16/41/L04
      (18th of 69 in Physics &amp;#8212; Condensed Matter, IF 2.55, 96 cites).
    

[4] "Size Effects on Thin Film Ferroelectrics: Experiments on
        Isolated Single Crystal Sheets", L. W. Chang, et al, Applied Physics
      Letters, 93, 132904 (2008). http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.2990760
      (17th of 125 in Physics &amp;#8212; Applied, IF 3.8, 31 cites)
    

[5] "Settling the Dead Layer Debate in Nanoscale Capacitors", L.
      W. Chang, et al, Advanced Materials 21, 4911 (2009). http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/adma.200901756
      (4th of 125 in Physics &amp;#8212; Applied, IF 13.9, 25 cites).
    

[6] "Strategies for gallium removal after focused ion beam patterning
        of ferroelectric oxide nanostructures", A. Schilling, et al,
      Nanotechnology 18, 035301 (2007). http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/18/3/035301
      (16th of 125 in Physics &amp;#8212; Applied, IF 4.0, 16 cites)
    
</References><ResearchSubjectAreas><SubjectArea><Level1>3</Level1><Level2>2</Level2><Subject>Inorganic Chemistry</Subject></SubjectArea><SubjectArea><Level1>9</Level1><Level2>12</Level2><Subject>Materials Engineering</Subject></SubjectArea><SubjectArea><Level1>2</Level1><Level2>99</Level2><Subject>Other Physical Sciences</Subject></SubjectArea></ResearchSubjectAreas><Sources>
    
      Letter from Business Development Manager, AVX Ltd. Coleraine
      Technical Report to AVX Ltd., 19 May 2011
      Northern Ireland's Top 100 Companies &amp;#8212; The Belfast Telegraph, 30 April
        2013,
        http://www.belfasttelegraph.co.uk/business/top-100-companies/company-list/87-avx-29216579.html

    
    </Sources><Title>
    Failure in Multilayer Ceramic Capacitors (MLCC's) for AVX Ltd.
    </Title><UKLocation><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>2652586</GeoNamesId><Name>Coleraine</Name></GeoLocation></UKLocation><UKRegion><GeoLocation><GeoNamesId>2641364</GeoNamesId><Name>Northern Ireland</Name></GeoLocation></UKRegion><UOA>Physics</UOA><UnderpinningResearch>
    In the mid-1990's, academic staff, Bowman and Gregg, initiated a research
      activity to map and understand the properties of micro- and nanoscale
      ferroelectrics. Ferroelectrics were receiving significant commercial
      interest in numerous capacitor applications/markets. A key element in the
      early research was the fabrication and functional characterisation of very
      simple thin film planar capacitor structures based on titanates. These
      were investigated in an attempt to elucidate fundamental reasons for the
      dramatic collapse in permittivity, that reduces device capacitance, with
      decreasing device thickness and which was not understood at the time [Reference
        1]. This was of great importance as titanates are of principal use
      for both commercial ceramic capacitors (circa 1012 components
      manufactured p.a.) such as the X7R devices and for novel high-K
      perovskite-based Dynamic Random Access Memory (DRAM) systems
      conceptualised at the time.
    While capacitor structures made in-house did allow useful insights [Reference
        2], it soon became clear that ferroelectric (dielectric) properties
      were so sensitive to defects, introduced during thin film growth, that a
      radically new experimental approach was needed. Thus, from 2002, a wholly
      novel programme in which thin film capacitors were made from small slices
      of ferroelectric cut from high purity single crystals using Focused Ion
      Beam (FIB) milling [Reference 3] was initiated. Functional
      characterisation of these relatively unclamped defect-free systems
      demonstrated that the permittivity did not necessarily collapse with
      dielectric thickness decrease at all and that the effect could be
      engineered out in real devices. Such insights were published in a number
      of articles between 2004 and 2009 [Reference 4, 5].
    At the same time as this FIB micro-machining work progressed that
      included further insights into damage mitigation [Reference 6] we
      commenced a Knowledge Transfer Partnership (KTP) with AVX Ltd. The
      three-year project from 2005-2007 worth &amp;#163;123K was titled "Critical
        interfaces in currently produced capacitors". The project engaged
      M.M. Saad, primary author of Reference 3, as the Knowledge Transfer
      Associate. The project combined precision micro-machining by FIB to
      isolate known and potential defects and regions of MLCCs for detailed
      chemical and structural analysis that would then be followed up via TEM
      (Transmission Electron Microscopy) and STEM (Scanning Transmission
      Electron Microscopy). In the programme the parts investigated covered X7R
      specifications for in consumer electronics applications through to those
      for high voltage automotive usage. This provided Bowman and Gregg with
      significant bilateral experience in handling of parts and establishing
      common terminological ground for the use of the research methodologies and
      results to be applied to evaluating the defects that arise in such
      commercial components.
    We note that associated research in thin film capacitors remains an
      active area of endeavour, most recently via Technology Strategy Board
      (TSB) support of a project "Advanced capacitors for energy storage"
      with Syfer Technology worth &amp;#163;164K in 2010-12 and has received significant
      recent press attention http://goo.gl/p1kp12.
      Such collaborations have tapped various aspects of the ferroelectrics
      expertise developed in Queen's, but microscopy and FIB-processing
      knowledge has been crucial in all collaborative research to date.
    </UnderpinningResearch></CaseStudyDump></ArrayOfCaseStudyDump>
